Finding Aid for Carl Cohen papers, 1950-2012
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Carl Cohen papers 1950-2012
Cohen, Carl, 1931-
68 linear feet
0731 Aa 2
Professor of Philosophy at The University of Michigan; correspondence; records of University of Michigan and other organizational activities; articles, books, and speeches; and topical files.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Professor Cohen (donor no. 9714 ) and came to the library in multiple accessions in 2006.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Carl Cohen is Professor of Philosophy at The University of Michigan where he has taught political philosophy, ethics, and logic since 1955. He was born April 30, 1931 in Brooklyn, New York. He received an A.B. from the University of Miami, an M.A. from the University of Illinois, a Ph.D. from the University of California at Los Angeles, and an honorary L.D. from Ripon College.
At the University of Michigan, Cohen was one of the founders of the Residential College, serving as Associate Director (1967-1972) and Acting Director (1981). In addition, Professor Cohen has served as Chairman of the University Senate, Faculty Assembly, and the Senate Advisory Committee on University Affairs of Michigan (1974-1975) and as a member of the Executive Committee of the University's College of Literature, Science, and the Arts (1977-1980). From 1985 to 1996, he also was Director of Program in Human Values in Medicine in the University of Michigan Medical School.
Outside the University, Carl Cohen served as Chairman of the American Civil Liberties Union of Michigan (1971-1974), and as a member of the National Board of Directors of the ACLU. He served as a labor/management arbitrator for the American Arbitration Association and for the Michigan Employment Relations Commission. He has taught as a visiting professor at universities in Peru, Israel, Hong Kong, Singapore, and New Zealand, at the Universities of Illinois and Miami, and at Davidson College in North Carolina.
Professor Cohen has published widely in learned journals (Ethics, The Journal of Philosophy The New England Journal of Medicine, and others) and frequently in journals of political and literary opinion (The Nation, Commentary, The Yale Review, and others). He is the author, among other titles, of Civil Disobedience (Columbia University Press), Democracy (The Free Press/Macmillan), Four Systems (Random House), and Naked Racial Preference (Madison Books, 1995). With Irving M. Copi he is co-author of Introduction to Logic, multiple editions (Macmillan/Prentice Hall). His writings and lectures reflect his interest in a variety of moral and ethical topics, including the use of animals in medical research, the theory and practice of democracy, and the politics and underlying philosophy of the law on such issues as affirmative action and civil disobedience.
Summary Contents List
biographical/Personal -- Boxes 1-4
Correspondence -- Box 5-18
University of Michigan
Residential College -- Boxes 19-24
Department of Philosophy -- Box 25
Senate Advisory Committee on University Affairs -- Boxes 26-27
University of Michigan Medical Center Ethics Committee -- Boxes 28-30
Committee to Review Grants for Clinical Research and Investigation Involving Human Rights -- Box 31
Ad Hoc Committee on Classified Research, 1986-1987 -- Box 32
Course and Teaching Materials -- Boxes 33-35
Other Professional Activities
Dearborn / Fairlane Program Committee -- Boxes 36-37
Visiting Appointments -- Box 38
American Civil Liberties Union -- Box 39-40 (part)
Warner / Lambert (Parke Davis) Animal Care and Use Committee -- Box 40 (part)
Labor and Grievance Arbitration -- Boxes 41-45
Topical and Name files
Affirmative Action (cases, correspondence, Michigan Civil Rights Initiative, speeches and writings) -- Boxes 46-47
Medical Ethics -- Boxes 48-49
General Subjects, 1963-1988 -- Boxes 50-52
People file, 1963-1988 -- Box 53
Combined People and General Subjects File, 1988-2001 -- Boxes 54-56
Program in Human Values in Medicine, 1985-1996 -- Boxes 57-60
Publications
Books, articles, and speeches -- Boxes 61-63
Manuscript drafts, galleys, etc. of Democracy and Civil Disobedience-- Boxes 64-68
The Carl Cohen papers is comprised of correspondence, memoranda, writings, and topical files reflecting his teaching and other responsibilities as a member of the faculty of the University of Michigan. In addition, other files document his activities in other organizations, such as the American Civil Liberties Union and as a labor and grievance arbitrator. Many of the files concern his continuing interest in such contemporary issues as affirmative action and the use of animals in medical research.
Subjects:
Cohen, Carl, 1931-; Affirmative action programs--Michigan.; Animal rights.; American Civil Liberties Union.; Medical ethics.; Philosophers--United States.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Philosophy.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan. Program in Human Values in Medicine.; University of Michigan. Residential College.
- Biographical / Personal
  - Vitas (Box 1)
  - Awards (Box 1)
  - Biographical clippings (Box 1)
  - Celebration of 50 years of teaching at the University of Michigan (Box 1)
  - Scholarships and fellowships (Box 1)
  - Military service (Box 1)
  - Memorabilia for inclusion in "scrapbook" (Box 1)
  - Course notes, term papers, theses (Box 2)
    (from the University of Miami, University of Illinois, and University of California, Los Angeles)
  - Course notes, term papers, theses (Box 3)
    (continued)
  - Course notes, term papers, theses (Box 4)
- Correspondence
  - 1950-1956 (Box 5)
  - 1956-1958 (while serving in the military), 2 folders (Box 5)
  - 1956-1958 (while serving in the military), 3 folders (Box 6)
  - 1956-1965 (Box 6)
  - 1965-1971 (Box 7)
  - 1971-1977 (Box 8)
  - 1977-1985 (Box 9)
  - 1985-1992 (Box 10)
  - 1992-1996 (Box 11)
  - 1996-1999 (Box 12)
  - 1999-2000 (Box 13)
  - 2000-2001 (Box 14)
  - 2001-2002 (Box 15)
  - 2002-2003 (Box 16)
  - 2003-2005 (Box 17)
  - 2005-2007 (Box 18)
  - Assorted dates 1980s-1990s (Box 18)
  - Karl letters (Box 18)
    (mainly thank yous and other letters of appreciation)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 18)
- University of Michigan
  - Residential College
    - Topical Files (Box 19)
    - Topical Files (Box 20)
    - Topical Files (Box 21)
    - Topical Files (Box 22)
    - Topical Files (Box 23)
    - Topical Files (Box 24)
  - Department of Philosophy
    - Departmental meetings and other materials (Box 25)
  - Senate Advisory Committee on University Affairs
    - Topical files (Box 26)
      (include SACUA Tenure Subcommittee)
    - Topical files (Box 27)
  - University of Michigan Medical Center Ethics Committee
    - Topical files (Box 28)
      (include transplantation ethics meetings)
    - Topical files (Box 29)
    - Topical files (Box 30)
  - Committee to Review Grants for Clinical Research and Investigation Involving Human Rights
    - Topical Files (Box 31)
  - Ad Hoc Committee on Classified Research 1986-1987
    - Topical Files (Box 32)
  - Course and Teaching Materials
    - Course proposals
      - Readings course--human values in medicine (Box 33)
      - Special topics in philosophy and medicine (Box 33)
    - Departmental rules (Box 33)
    - Lectures
      - Aesthetics and the Arts 1973 (RC Core 204) (Box 33)
      - Introduction to Clinical Sciences (ICS)
        - Evaluations (Box 33)
        - Exams (Box 33)
        - Issues (Box 33)
        - Lectures (Box 33)
        - Multidisciplinary conference 1992 (heart defects) (Box 33)
        - Phi Chi notes 1987-1988, 2 folders (Box 33)
        - Schedule
          - 1988 (Box 33)
          - 1990 (Box 33)
      - ICS 500
        - Exams
          - 1985, 2 folders (Box 33)
          - 1986 (Box 33)
          - 1989 (Box 33)
        - Handouts
          - 1985-1988, 4 folders (Box 33)
          - 1990 (Box 33)
        - Lecture notes
          - 1. Health and disease, 2 folders (Box 33)
          - 2. The patient as person: autonomy and paternalism, 4 folders (Box 33)
          - 3. Experimenting on human beings: informed consent (Box 33)
          - 4. Medicine, morals and money, 4 folders (Box 33)
        - Schedule
          - 1987 (Box 33)
          - 1989 (Box 33)
      - ICS 501
        - Exam addendum 1992 (Box 33)
      - ICS 600
        - Exam 1991 (Box 33)
        - Handouts
          - 1985-1988 (Box 33)
        - Lecture notes
          - 1. Confidentiality, 4 folders (Box 33)
          - 2. Truth-telling, 4 folders (Box 33)
          - 3. Withdrawal of treatment (Box 33)
      - ICS 601
        - Evaluation 1986 (Box 33)
        - Exams
          - Notes (Box 33)
          - 1986-1990, 6 folders (Box 33)
        - Lecture notes
          - 2. Moral issues in terminal care, 3 folders (Box 33)
      - List of philosophers (letter to Irv Copi) (Box 33)
      - Logic and Language (RC Core 105)
        - 1975-1976, 2 folders (Box 33)
        - 1984 (Box 33)
        - 1986-1993, 9 folders (Box 33)
        - Copi/Bischoff correspondence (Box 33)
        - Evaluations 1987 (Box 33)
        - Exams
          - General, 2 folders (Box 33)
          - 1967-1968, 2 folders (Box 33)
          - 1970-1971, 2 folders (Box 33)
          - 1982 (Box 33)
          - 1985 (Box 33)
          - 1987-1989, 3 folders (Box 33)
          - 1992-1994, 3 folders (Box 33)
        - Informal seminar 1968 (Box 33)
        - Materials (Box 33)
        - Memos (Box 33)
        - Plans, sketches (Box 33)
      - Michigan Scholarship 1971 (Box 33)
      - Philosophical Bases of Communism, Fascism, and Democracy (Philosophy 363)
        - 1966 (Box 33)
        - 1971 (Box 33)
        - 1974 (Box 33)
        - 1977 (Box 33)
        - 1980-1981, 2 folders (Box 33)
        - 1985, 2 folders (Box 33)
        - 1988-1989, 2 folders (Box 33)
        - 1992 (Box 33)
        - Exams
          - General, 3 folders (Box 34)
          - 1980 (Box 34)
          - 1984 (Box 34)
          - 1985 (Box 34)
          - 1987-1990, 4 folders (Box 34)
          - 1992-1993, 2 folders (Box 34)
        - Plan to offer (Box 34)
        - Syllabus (Box 34)
      - Philosophy 63, 2 folders (Box 34)
      - Philosophy 234 1966 (Box 34)
      - Philosophy 263 (Box 34)
      - Philosophy and Public Affairs (RC Humanities 470) (Box 34)
      - Philosophy of Religion (Box 34)
      - Social Philosophy (Philosophy 141) (Box 34)
      - Other lectures
        - School of Dentistry, ethics overview 1988 (Box 34)
        - Genetics lecture 1987 (Box 34)
        - Inteflex 1986 (Box 34)
        - Interphase Program 1988 (Box 34)
    - Student evaluations, 3 folders (Box 34)
    - Syllabi (Philosophy 34, 51, 124, 64) (Box 34)
    - Text assignments (Box 34)
    - Texts 1973-1975, 2 folders (Box 34)
    - Lecture notes circa 1959-1973 (Box 35)
      (formerly in binders)
- Other Professional Activities
  - Dearborn / Fairlane Program Committee
    - Topical Files (Box 36)
    - Topical Files (Box 37)
  - Visiting Appointments
    - To China, Peru, Davidson College, New Zealand, etc. (Box 38)
  - American Civil Liberties Union
    - Topical files
      - Access to media 1972-1974 (Box 39)
      - Commercial speech 1974-1975 (Box 39)
      - Discrimination in private organizations 1971-1972 (Box 39)
      - Mazey, Ernie 1974 (Box 39)
      - Military recruiting on campus (Box 39)
      - Neier, A., Ennis, E. 1971 (Box 39)
      - Press shield 1973 (Box 39)
      - Reitman, Alan 1974 (Box 39)
      - Searches 1971-1972 (Box 39)
      - Seat belt correspondence 1973 (Box 39)
      - Shockley, et. al. 1974 (Box 39)
      - Wiretap bill 1972 (Box 39)
    - National
      - Elections 1977 (Box 39)
      - Procedures 1974, 2 folders (Box 39)
      - Science and civil liberties 1975-1977, 2 folders (Box 39)
    - State branch
      (American Civil Liberties Union of Michigan)
      - Topical
        - General
          - 1967-1968, 2 folders (Box 39)
          - 1974-1975 (Box 39)
        - Addresses 1973-1974 (Box 39)
        - Executive Directors 1974 (Box 39)
        - Expense policy correspondence 1975 (Box 39)
        - House Internal Security Commission 1972 (Box 39)
        - Lawyer's committee 1972-1973 (Box 39)
        - Marovich complaint 1974 (Box 39)
        - Rave, Mary 1974 (Box 39)
        - Reports to Michigan on national board 1974 (Box 39)
        - Workshop 1974 (Box 39)
      - Chronological
        - General 1971-1975, 2 folders (Box 39)
        - 1974, 2 folders (Box 39)
        - 1975, 7 folders (Box 39)
    - Regional branches
      - Central Michigan (Box 39)
      - Northwest Michigan (Box 39)
      - Western Michigan (Box 39)
    - Local branches
      - Ann Arbor 1967, 1973, 2 folders (Box 40)
      - Flint 1972-1973 (Box 40)
      - Kalamazoo 1971-1973 (Box 40)
      - Lansing 1971-1973 (Box 40)
      - Metropolitan Detroit 1971-1973 (Box 40)
  - Warner / Lambert (Parke Davis) Animal Care and Use Committee
    - Topical Files 1987-1989 (Box 40)
  - Labor and Grievance Arbitration
    - Decisions and other working files (Box 41)
    - Decisions and other working files (Box 42)
    - Decisions and other working files (Box 43)
    - Decisions and other working files (Box 44)
  - Podolsky and allied cases
    (CC was called as expert medical witness)
    - Depositions and related files (Box 45)
- Topical and Name files
  - Affirmative Action
    - Cases
      - Bakke
        - Correspondence
          - Miscellaneous (Box 46)
          - American Association of University Professors 1977 (Box 46)
          - American Civil Liberties Union 1978 (Box 46)
          - Chronicle of Higher Education 1977 (Box 46)
          - Colvin, Reynold H. (Allan Bakke's lawyer) 1977 (Box 46)
          - Michigan Daily 1977 (Box 46)
          - New York Times 1977 (Box 46)
          - New York Times, Rush letter and reply 1977 (Box 46)
          - Newsweek 1978 (Box 46)
          - Van Alstyne, William 1979 (Box 46)
        - Writings
          - The Bakke Decision: Equality, Diversity, and Good Faith, undated, 3 folders (Box 46)
          - Diversity, Race, and University Admissions (Box 46)
          - On Diversity, Individual Treatment, and Good Faith, undated (Box 46)
          - On Diversity, Individuality, and Good Faith, undated (Box 46)
          - On Preference by Race, undated (Box 46)
        - Other
          - Post-Bakke (the Meaning of Bakke) (Box 46)
          - Regional Post-Bakke Conference 1978 (Box 46)
      - DeFunis
        - Amintaphil Conference, remarks, replies, comments to Cohen 1974 (Box 46)
        - Correspondence 1972-1975, 2 folders (Box 46)
        - The DeFunis Case: Race & the Constitution 1975 (Box 46)
        - Honorable Ends, Unsavory Means: DeFunis Revisited, undated (Box 46)
        - Preferential Admissions and Equal Protection of the Laws (Box 46)
      - Gratz
        - Court 2000 (Box 46)
        - The Journal of Blacks in Higher Education 1997 (Box 46)
        - Kolbo, Kirk 1997 (Box 46)
      - Weber
        - General 1979 (Box 46)
        - Equal Protection and the Intent of Congress, 3 folders (Box 46)
        - Justice Debased: The Weber Decision, 1979 (Box 46)
        - On Race and Jobs: Racial Preference in Employment, undated (Box 46)
      - Wygan 1985 (Box 46)
    - Course, Race and Admissions 2005 (Box 46)
    - Correspondence
      - Miscellaneous (Box 46)
      - E-mail responses 1997 (Box 46)
      - By Correspondent
        - Adelson, Joseph 1990 (Box 46)
        - Bergman, Jay 1996 (Box 46)
        - Cahn, Steve 1989-1993 (Box 46)
        - California Civil Rights Initiative (Ward Connerly) 1996 (Box 46)
        - Center for Equal Opportunity 1996 (Box 46)
        - Center for Individual Rights 1995-1996 (Box 46)
        - Christie, Jim 1996 (Box 46)
        - Duderstadt, James J. 1996 (Box 46)
        - Faculty Affairs 1994 (Box 46)
        - Favish, Allan 1996, 2 folders (Box 46)
        - Fay, Tim 2006 (Box 46)
        - Institute for the Study of Educational Policy 1975 (Box 46)
        - Kahn, Douglas 1992 (Box 46)
        - Kolbo, Kirk 1997-2002 (Box 46)
        - Lynch, Fred 1991-1993 (Box 46)
        - Marxer, Joseph 1994 (Box 46)
        - Michigan Alumnus 1998 (Box 46)
        - Michigan Association of Scholars 2002 (Box 46)
        - National Association of Scholars 1993 (Box 46)
        - Oade, Preston 1979 (Box 46)
        - Pell, Terence 2006 (Box 46)
        - Perry, Barbara 2006 (Box 46)
        - Purdy, Larry 2000-2001, 2 folders (Box 46)
        - Rosenwald, George C. 2006 (Box 46)
        - Sandalow, Terrance 1975-1977, 2001 (Box 46)
        - Sher, George 1980 (Box 46)
        - Sterba, James 2000-2003, 2 folders (Box 46)
        - University of Syracuse (Jonathan Greenfield) 1994 (Box 46)
        - Weisbach, Mike 2002 (Box 46)
      - By Topic
        - Affirmative Action in Medical Schools (Box 47)
        - Equal Opportunity Act of 1995 1995 (Box 47)
        - Ethnic proportional representation, Ann Arbor News 1999 (Box 47)
        - Freedom of Information Act 1991 (Box 47)
        - Hopwood v. Texas 1994 (Box 47)
        - Minority Research 1989 (Box 47)
        - Quotas 1973 (Box 47)
        - Title VI and 14th amendment 2002-2003 (Box 47)
      - Schools
        - Baylor/Clemson University 1993 (Box 47)
        - California State University-Chico 1994 (Box 47)
        - Dartmouth College 1993 (Box 47)
        - Harvard University 1992 (Box 47)
        - Law schools 1976-1977 (Box 47)
        - Tougaloo College 1991 (Box 47)
        - University of Michigan 1992 (Box 47)
        - University of Texas-Austin 1992 (Box 47)
        - University of Windsor 1992 (Box 47)
    - Michigan Civil Rights Initiative
      - Correspondence
        - General 2003-2005, 2 folders (Box 47)
        - Ann Arbor news advertisement 2005 (Box 47)
        - Letters to the editor 2005 (Box 47)
        - University of Michigan campaign participation 2006 (Box 47)
      - Speeches and debates
        - General 2005-2006 (Box 47)
        - Asian Pacific American Law Students Association panel 2006 (Box 47)
        - Mackinac Policy Conference panel 2005 (Box 47)
        - Michigan State University, debate 2006 (Box 47)
    - Speeches
      - Affirmative Action: An Issue of Many Colors Michigan Association of Governing Boards of State Universities, 1996 (Box 47)
      - Affirmative Action and Racial Preference
        - American Association of University Professors 1996 (Box 47)
        - Michigan Hearing, Shelby Township 1997 (Box 47)
        - Tufts University 1996 (Box 47)
      - The Impact of Preference by Group, Hillsdale College, 1996 (Box 47)
      - Michigan State Senate, Testimony of Carl Cohen 1998 (Box 47)
      - Is Preferential Affirmative Action Just? When is Affirmative Action Right? 1997 (Box 47)
      - Racial Preference in the University University of Miami, 1997 (Box 47)
      - "Transition 2000 and Beyond," affirmative action debate with Brent Simmons, Lansing, Department of Transportation, 1996 (Box 47)
      - Untitled, D.C. Hillel 1990 (Box 47)
      - Untitled, Law School, MSU and Detroit College of Law, Lansing 1998 (Box 47)
      - U.S. House of Representatives, Committee on the Judiciary, Subcommittee on the Constitution, Carl Cohen testimony 1995 (Box 47)
      - What is Affirmative Action?, Mackinac Island, Detroit Chamber of Commerce, 2005 (Box 47)
    - Writings
      - Affirmative Action and the Rights of the Majority, 1983 (Box 47)
      - Affirmative Action book undated, 2 folders (Box 47)
      - Affirmative Action in Medical School Admissions 1981 (Box 47)
      - Articles (Box 47)
      - The Corruption that is Group Preference, 1997 (Box 47)
      - "Diversity" and Bad Faith (New York Times op-ed), 1996 (Box 47)
      - Diversity, Race, and University Admission undated (Box 47)
      - Drafts (Box 47)
      - The Equal Protection of the Laws (Detroit News op-ed), 1997 (Box 47)
      - Naked Racial Preference (Box 47)
      - The Penalty of Preference, 1992, 2 folders (Box 47)
      - Race and Equal Protection of the Laws, 1977
        - Correspondence 1977 (Box 47)
        - Drafts (Box 47)
        - Outline (original, drafts, and final) (Box 47)
        - Final (Box 47)
      - Race in University of Michigan Admissions 1996-1997, 2 folders (Box 47)
      - Race, Lies, and "Hopwood," 1996 (Box 47)
      - Racial Discrimination in Admissions at the University of Michigan 1996-1997 (Box 47)
      - Racial Discrimination is Immoral and Unlawful (Box 47)
      - Racial Discrimination, Not Inclusion, is the Target (Box 47)
      - Review, Discrimination and Reverse Discrimination, by Kent Greenawalt, 2 folders (Box 47)
      - The Rise and Fall of Diversity undated (Box 47)
      - Should Federal Affirmative Action Policies Be Continued? 1996 (Box 47)
      - The Supreme Court's Flirtation with Racism in Pursuit of Equality 1979 (Box 47)
      - What is "Affirmative Action"? undated (Box 47)
      - Who Are Equals? 1978 (Box 47)
      - Who Bears the Burden of Racially Preferential Affirmative Action? 1997 (Box 47)
      - Defunis-honorable ends, unsavory means: Defunis revisited (Box 47)
      - Bakke -- Race and the Equal protection of the laws, diversity race and university admission, the uses of race in admissions under regents v. Bakke (Box 47)
      - Weber-Equal protection and the intent of Congress, justice debased, on race and jobs (Box 47)
  - Medical Ethics: lectures, notes, writings
    - Abortion
      - Abortion and privacy, 2 folders (Box 48)
      - Abortion, Rights, and Democracy (Box 48)
      - Abortion/teens (Box 48)
      - Lecture notes (Box 48)
      - When does life begin? (Box 48)
    - AIDS/HIV
      - AIDS/HIV test (Box 48)
      - Hastings Center case commentary (Box 48)
    - Alcoholics, 4 folders (Box 48)
    - Anencephalic donation of organs (Box 48)
    - Animals
      - Animal Experimentation Defended
        - Istituto di Ricerche Farmacologiche "Mario Negri" 1988 (Box 48)
        - Johnson and Johnson 1989 (Box 48)
      - Animals, Obligations, and Research (Box 48)
      - Animals/physiology (Box 48)
      - Ann Arbor Association for Responsible Animal Treatment (Box 48)
      - The Case for the Use of Animals in Biomedical Research
        - Article (Box 48)
        - Letters and responses, 5 folders (Box 48)
      - Correspondence, 2 folders (Box 48)
      - Do Animals Have Rights? 1995 (Box 48)
      - Kaldjian article comments 1987 (Box 48)
      - May We Patent Animal Lives? (Box 48)
      - Notes (Box 48)
      - Restricting Research on Moral Grounds 1988 (Box 48)
      - The Use of Animals in Research Defended (Box 48)
      - Why Animals Have No Rights (Box 48)
    - Assisted suicide
      - Ethics of Assisted Suicide, 1995 (Box 48)
      - Futile medical intervention 1993 (Box 48)
    - Autonomy
      - Autonomy and paternalism (Box 48)
      - Refusing Blood--Autonomy, Paternalism, and Jehovah's Witnesses 1993 (Box 48)
    - Birth defects (Birth Defects: Moral Issues and Genetic Detection) (Box 48)
    - Blood
      - Increasing the Safety of Our Blood Supply: What are the Costs? 1989 (Box 48)
    - Brain death (Brain Death--Whole Brain or Higher Brain? And Why?) (Box 48)
    - Civil Disobedience (Civil Disobedience in Defense of Fetuses, Animals, and the Victims of AIDS), 1989 (Box 48)
    - Confidentiality
      - Confidentiality and the Primacy of Care, 1992 (Box 48)
      - Confidentiality and research 1991 (Box 48)
    - Damaged neonate (The Severely Damaged Neonate) (Box 48)
    - Dead bodies
      - The Case for Presumed Consent to Transplant Human Organs After Death, 1981 (Box 48)
      - Presuming consent in the use of dead bodies
        - Correspondence 1985-1986, 4 folders (Box 48)
        - Lecture notes (Box 48)
    - Death
      - Death and dying 1975 (Box 48)
      - What is Death? 1994 (Box 48)